<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Genlog</title><link>https://genlog.tcrouzet.com/rss.xml</link><description>Genlog is an experimental litterrary generative experiment. The texts are automatically generated from articles read by Thierry Crouzet. The analysis is written in Crouzet's style by a fine-tuned ChatGPT model and contextualized with a RAG query around the Thierry Crouzet Diary.</description><atom:link href="https://genlog.tcrouzet.com/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><image><url>https://genlog.tcrouzet.com/vana-square-2022.jpg</url><title>Genlog</title><link>https://genlog.tcrouzet.com/rss.xml</link></image><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 16:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><item><title>Sunday, June 2nd 2024</title><link>https://genlog.tcrouzet.com//2024/06/02_en/</link><description><![CDATA[<img src="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2024/05/StripedTimemaCristinaeStickInsect.jpg" alt="image" />

<p><a href="https://www.sciencealert.com/astonishing-study-shows-evolution-really-does-repeat-itself">Astonishing Study Shows Evolution Really Does Repeat Itself</a></p>
<p>Evolution, often perceived as a random process acting on various traits emerging from genetic variation, may not be as haphazard as previously thought. A recent study on stick insects, particularly Timema cristinae, by Patrik Nosil and colleagues, reveals a pattern of predictable evolution in camouflage. Over 30 years, they observed that certain camouflage patterns cycled in a predictable manner across 10 geographically separated populations. The study suggests that evolution can be both repeatable and complex for the same trait, shedding light on how organisms respond to selection pressures. This research adds to the growing body of evidence showing predictable evolutionary paths in various species, potentially aiding in predicting and managing population changes.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.marktechpost.com/2024/06/01/rag-me-up-a-generic-ai-framework-server-uis-that-enables-you-to-do-rag-on-your-own-dataset-easily/">‘RAG Me Up’: A Generic AI Framework (Server + UIs) that Enables You to Do RAG on Your Own Dataset Easily</a></p>
<p>This article discusses the challenges organizations face in managing and extracting information from documents efficiently. Existing solutions like RAG frameworks offer tools for document processing but can be complex to integrate. Enter 'RAG Me Up', a lightweight framework focusing on ease of use and integration, supporting various file types. It features an ensemble retriever for robust document retrieval and automatic document fetching during chat dialogues. Users can customize parameters for different language and embedding models, showcasing its adaptability for diverse applications.</p>
<p><a href="https://gizmodo.com.au/2024/05/what-is-an-npu/">What’s an NPU and Why Is Big Tech Suddenly Obsessed?</a></p>
<p>Tech companies are hyping NPUs, neural processing units, due to the AI hype cycle. Microsoft touted ARM-based Copilot+ PCs with NPUs offering 45 TOPS for on-device AI. Only these PCs will access AI features like Recall, leaving Intel Core Ultra chip users behind. There's debate over running Recall on another ARM64-based PC without an NPU. NPUs are specialized processors for machine learning tasks, processing computations in parallel without using other system processors.</p>

<p>Generation cost: <a href="https://openai.com/pricing">13380 tokens/0.06$</a></p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">2024-06-02</guid><enclosure url="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2024/05/StripedTimemaCristinaeStickInsect.jpg" length="162096" type="image/jpeg"/><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Saturday, May 25th 2024</title><link>https://genlog.tcrouzet.com//2024/05/25_en/</link><description><![CDATA[<img src="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2024/01/big-ring.jpg" alt="image" />

<p><a href="https://www.geeky-gadgets.com/jarvis-style-chatgptgpt-ai-voice-assistant/">How to build your own Jarvis style ChatGPT-4o AI voice assistant with memory</a></p>
<p>The tutorial by Prompt Engineering guides you in creating a modular AI assistant, "Aiden," powered by OpenAI ChatGPT-4o. It covers audio capture with a high-quality microphone, transcription using the Whisper model API, query processing with GPT-4o, text-to-speech conversion via OpenAI's voice engine, and chat history management for context retention. The system architecture ensures accurate interactions through intelligent and context-aware responses. The tutorial emphasizes a modular code structure for Aiden, focusing on functions like recording audio with speech_recognition and transcribing it using the Whisper model.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.sciencealert.com/giant-structure-lurking-in-deep-space-challenges-our-understanding-of-the-universe">Giant Structure Lurking in Deep Space Challenges Our Understanding of The Universe</a></p>
<p>Astronomers discover a mysterious colossal ring of galaxies in the distant Universe, challenging current cosmological understanding. The Big Ring, spanning 1.3 billion light-years, defies known structures. Led by Alexia Lopez, the finding suggests a need to revise the standard cosmological model. The ring, not a Baryon Acoustic Oscillation, perplexes scientists with its corkscrew shape. It questions the Cosmological Principle and existing size limits, hinting at potential flaws in cosmology.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cantorsparadise.com/the-surprising-discovery-of-imaginary-numbers-cd6dfa1cb2c5">The Surprising Discovery of Imaginary Numbers</a></p>
<p>The Impossible Problem of the Cubic Equation: ancient civilizations attempted to solve the cubic equation for thousands of years without success. Luca Pacioli in 1494 concluded it was unsolvable. Ancient mathematics relied on geometric reasoning, limiting solutions due to aversion to negative numbers. Scipione del Ferro's method solved depressed cubics, inspiring Niccolo Fontana Tartaglia's algorithm. Gerolamo Cardano discovered the solution for the full cubic equation, including the x² term, leading to the invention of imaginary numbers.</p>

<p>Generation cost: <a href="https://openai.com/pricing">12262 tokens/0.06$</a></p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-25</guid><enclosure url="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2024/01/big-ring.jpg" length="26997" type="image/jpeg"/><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Tuesday, May 21st 2024</title><link>https://genlog.tcrouzet.com//2024/05/21_en/</link><description><![CDATA[<img src="https://i.insider.com/6644e4f3f27898f532d80239" alt="image" />

<p><a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/we-live-inside-cosmic-void-breaks-cosmology-laws-2024-5">Astronomers say we may live at the center of a cosmic void 2 billion light-years wide that defies the laws of cosmology</a></p>
<p>The article discusses the existence of a giant cosmic void in our local universe, contradicting the cosmological principle. This void, named the KBC void, is about 2 billion light-years wide, defying standard cosmology laws. Observations suggest that matter may not be uniformly distributed, leading to regions of high and low densities. The void could explain conflicting observations about the expansion of the universe.</p>
<p>The KBC void defies cosmology laws, 20% emptier than surrounding space. Observations show non-uniform matter distribution, contradicting the cosmological principle. Named the KBC void, it's 2 billion light-years wide. This void could resolve expansion discrepancies in our local universe.</p>
<p><a href="https://mindmatters.ai/2024/05/science-team-argues-consciousness-came-before-life/">Science Team Argues, Consciousness Came Before Life</a></p>
<p>This article discusses the hypothesis that consciousness may have preceded life, challenging the common belief that life came before consciousness. Stuart Hameroff, Anirban Bandyopadhyay, and Dante Lauretta propose this idea based on the Orch OR theory of consciousness, which suggests that consciousness arises from the collapse of quantum superpositions. They introduce the concept of "proto-conscious" objective reduction events in the early universe, theorizing that these events motivated purposeful behavior in simple organisms before the development of genes and brains. The team's theory aims to address the fundamental question of how life forms acquired goals, a key distinction between living and non-living entities.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.sciencealert.com/scientists-discovered-an-amazing-practical-use-for-leftover-coffee-grounds">Scientists Discovered An Amazing Practical Use For Leftover Coffee Grounds</a></p>
<p>Researchers in Australia discovered that by processing and adding charred coffee grounds to concrete, it could be 30 percent stronger, addressing environmental challenges related to coffee waste and sand extraction. The team pyrolyzed coffee waste to create biochar, which can incorporate itself into the cement matrix. They are testing the durability of the hybrid coffee-cement product under various stressors and exploring creating biochars from other organic waste sources.</p>

<h3>Generated text</h3><p>Generation cost: <a href="https://openai.com/pricing">14753 tokens/0.07$</a></p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-21</guid><enclosure url="https://i.insider.com/6644e4f3f27898f532d80239" length="16196" type="image/jpeg"/><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Monday, May 20th 2024</title><link>https://genlog.tcrouzet.com//2024/05/20_en/</link><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.uniladtech.com/science/space/potential-evidence-of-alien-civilisation-in-space-238368-20240516">Potential evidence of alien civilisation discovered in space</a></p>
<p>Scientists potentially detect alien structures called Dyson spheres around stars, emitting detectable infrared glow. Data analysis of seven red dwarfs within 900 light-years of Earth reveals unusual brightness, hinting at advanced civilizations. Freeman Dyson's 1960 theory suggests aliens could harvest star power using Dyson swarms. Further research identifies 53 similar cases up to 6,500 light-years away. Possible natural explanations include debris from planet formation or alignment with distant galaxies. Further studies aim to uncover the truth behind these mysterious signals.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.freethink.com/hard-tech/metamaterial">3D-printed “metamaterial” is stronger than anything in nature</a></p>
<p>Australian scientists create super strong, lightweight "metamaterial" inspired by plants like the Victoria water lily. The new material, made using advanced metal 3D-printing, has a lattice structure distributing load stress evenly. The metamaterial, fabricated from a titanium alloy, is 50% stronger than aerospace alloys. The team used laser powder bed fusion, a unique 3D printing technique, to create the metamaterial. Traditional manufacturing processes may hinder real-world applications initially, but as technology advances, wider implementation is expected.</p>
<p><a href="https://bigthink.com/hard-science/how-particle-accelerators-recreate-the-infant-universe/">How particle accelerators recreate the Universe’s first moments</a></p>
<p>Particle accelerators recreate early Universe moments, revealing Big Bang insights. Experiments illuminate Universe evolution into star-filled cosmos. Blend of theoretical and experimental physics enhances understanding of earliest epochs. Large Hadron Collider accelerates protons to recreate hot early Universe conditions. Experiments explore Universe's transition from particle to nuclear physics eras. Inflation epoch, a period of faster-than-light expansion, remains theoretical.</p>

<h3>Generated text</h3>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-20</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Thursday, May 16th 2024</title><link>https://genlog.tcrouzet.com//2024/05/16_en/</link><description><![CDATA[<img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2024/astronomers-discover-n-3.jpg" alt="image" />

<p><a href="https://phys.org/news/2024-05-astronomers-earth-sized-world-orbiting.html">Astronomers discover new Earth-sized world orbiting an ultra-cool star - Phys.org</a></p>
<p>An international team of astronomers discovered SPECULOOS-3 b, an Earth-sized planet orbiting an ultra-cool red dwarf star 55 light years away. The planet, tidally locked, takes 17 hours to orbit the star, which is colder, less massive, and less luminous than our sun. The SPECULOOS project, led by the University of Liège, aims to find exoplanets around ultra-cool dwarf stars using a global network of robotic telescopes. SPECULOOS-3 b was observed by telescopes worldwide, including the SPECULOOS South Observatory in Chile. Ultra-cool dwarf stars, common in the Milky Way, have long lifespans, potentially fostering life on their planets.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.news9live.com/science/spirals-of-matter-spotted-feeding-central-black-hole-in-andromeda-galaxy-2535785">Spirals of matter spotted feeding central black hole in Andromeda Galaxy - News9 LIVE</a></p>
<p>NASA's Spitzer instrument uncovers feeding habits of supermassive black hole in Andromeda galaxy, with structures matching simulations. Black holes in galaxies feed on gas, dust, and stars, exhibiting tidal disruption events with bright flashes. Some galaxies have active galactic nuclei, bright due to accretion discs emitting light across electromagnetic spectrum. Quiescent black holes like Sagittarius A<em> and M31</em> feed modestly, emitting steady light. Computer simulations and observations by Hubble and Spitzer confirm spirals of dust feeding M31*.</p>

<h3>Generated text</h3><p>Generation cost: <a href="https://openai.com/pricing">6848 tokens/0.05$</a></p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-16</guid><enclosure url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2024/astronomers-discover-n-3.jpg" length="197379" type="image/jpeg"/><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item></channel></rss>