<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Daylog</title><link>https://daylog.tcrouzet.com/rss_en.xml</link><description>Daylog is a newsletter automatically generated from articles read by Thierry Crouzet over the last 24 hours.
    The analysis is written in Crouzet's style by a fine-tuned ChatGPT model and contextualized with a RAG query around the Thierry Crouzet Diary.</description><atom:link href="https://daylog.tcrouzet.com/rss_en.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><image><url>https://daylog.tcrouzet.com/vana-square-2022.jpg</url><title>Daylog</title><link>https://daylog.tcrouzet.com/rss_en.xml</link></image><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 16:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><item><title>Thursday, May 16th 2024</title><link>https://daylog.tcrouzet.com/2024/05/16_en/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://phys.org/news/2024-05-astronomers-earth-sized-world-orbiting.html"&gt;Astronomers discover new Earth-sized world orbiting an ultra-cool star - Phys.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An international team of astronomers discovered SPECULOOS-3 b, an Earth-sized planet orbiting an ultra-cool red dwarf star 55 light years away. The planet, tidally locked, takes 17 hours to orbit the star, which is colder, less massive, and less luminous than our sun. The SPECULOOS project, led by the University of Liège, aims to find exoplanets around ultra-cool dwarf stars using a global network of robotic telescopes. SPECULOOS-3 b was observed by telescopes worldwide, including the SPECULOOS South Observatory in Chile. Ultra-cool dwarf stars, common in the Milky Way, have long lifespans, potentially fostering life on their planets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.news9live.com/science/spirals-of-matter-spotted-feeding-central-black-hole-in-andromeda-galaxy-2535785"&gt;Spirals of matter spotted feeding central black hole in Andromeda Galaxy - News9 LIVE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA's Spitzer instrument uncovers feeding habits of supermassive black hole in Andromeda galaxy, with structures matching simulations. Black holes in galaxies feed on gas, dust, and stars, exhibiting tidal disruption events with bright flashes. Some galaxies have active galactic nuclei, bright due to accretion discs emitting light across electromagnetic spectrum. Quiescent black holes like Sagittarius A&lt;em&gt; and M31&lt;/em&gt; feed modestly, emitting steady light. Computer simulations and observations by Hubble and Spitzer confirm spirals of dust feeding M31*.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Analyse&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The universe reminds us of our insignificance, yet we continue to explore. The announcement of the discovery of SPECULOOS-3 b, an Earth-sized exoplanet, has the same effect on me as Proxima Centauri. I am eager to find another habitable planet, yet I mock us, as we are unable to take care of our own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spirals of matter plunging into the central black hole of the Andromeda galaxy fascinate me just as much. They remind me of the spirals of my nocturnal thoughts, where I try to connect black holes to consciousness. These phenomena, so distant from us, show our capacity to contemplate the infinite. They push us towards both humility and audacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are explorers, seeking to understand, to surpass ourselves, to expand our territory, while remaining human beings. Ultimately, we seek a mirror for our soul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generation cost: &lt;a href="https://openai.com/pricing"&gt;6848 tokens/0.05$&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-16</guid><enclosure url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2024/astronomers-discover-n-3.jpg" length="197379" type="image/jpeg"/><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Tuesday, May 14th 2024</title><link>https://daylog.tcrouzet.com/2024/05/14_en/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://theconversation.com/dancing-raisins-a-simple-kitchen-experiment-reveals-how-objects-can-extract-energy-from-their-environment-and-come-to-life-223255"&gt;'Dancing' raisins − a simple kitchen experiment reveals how objects can extract energy from their environment and come to life - The Conversation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kitchen serves as a unique laboratory for exploring soft matter and complex fluids, leading to discoveries at the intersection of physics and chemistry. A study in Nature Communications by Sam Christianson, Carsen Grote, and others delves into the phenomenon of objects levitating in carbonated fluids, known as dancing raisins. This study unveils how objects like raisins rhythmically move up and down in carbonated fluids for extended periods. The formation of bubbles in carbonated beverages is a result of gas escaping when the fluid pressure drops upon opening, with surface tension and container rough patches enabling bubble growth. Raisins, with their wrinkly surfaces, are exceptional at inducing bubble formation and showcasing a lively dance in carbonated drinks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scitechdaily.com/quantum-mystery-solved-scientists-shed-light-on-perplexing-high-temperature-superconductors/"&gt;Quantum Mystery Solved – Scientists Shed Light on Perplexing High-Temperature Superconductors - SciTechDaily&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flatiron Institute scientist Shiwei Zhang and team use Hubbard model to recreate cuprate superconductivity features. Understanding cuprates could lead to superfast trains and MRI advancements. Recent Science paper details breakthrough in high-temperature superconductivity origins. Zhang's team enhances 2D Hubbard model with diagonal electron hops, capturing cuprate superconductivity. Cuprates surprise with superconductivity at relatively higher temperatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nanowerk.com/news2/space/newsid=65208.php"&gt;A new process for the synthesis of rare nuclei in the Universe? - Nanowerk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists propose the νr-process, involving neutrinos and neutron-rich material, as a new nucleosynthesis process to explain the origin of p-nuclei in the solar system. This process allows for the production of rare isotopes like 92,94Mo, 96,98Ru, and 92Nb through neutrino catalyzed capture reactions. The νr-process operates in neutron-rich outflows in astrophysical explosions, converting neutrons bound in nuclei into protons with the help of neutrinos, producing neutron-deficient nuclei. The type of stellar explosion where the νr-process occurs is yet to be determined, with suggestions including magneto-rotational supernovae, collapsars, or magnetars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Analyse&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientific exploration is like riding a bike on the Larzac plateau: we never really know where it will lead us, but the journey itself is worth the detour. I delved into three articles that, at first glance, seem as disparate as bottles of San Pellegrino and Gatorade used to build a model of an orbital base. Yet, upon closer inspection, they reveal a fascinating common thread: our relentless quest to understand the universe, from dancing grapes to superconductors, passing through the synthesis of rare nuclei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first article, on dancing grapes, reminds me that science can be playful and accessible, much like building a model from scratch with Émile. It is the wonder at everyday phenomena that drives us to explore further, to seek explanations beyond the obvious. Superconductors and the synthesis of rare nuclei, on the other hand, delve into the depths of matter and the universe, echoing reflections on neural networks and the modeling of the universe. These studies point towards a complex and beautifully structured reality, where each discovery brings us closer to a deeper understanding, yet inevitably raises new questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, these articles, much like excerpts from my journal, illustrate our innate desire to push the boundaries of our knowledge, to play with concepts to see where they can lead us. Whether by observing grapes in sparkling water, deciphering the mysteries of superconductivity, or proposing new nucleosynthesis processes, we are constantly in search of answers, knowing that each answer is just a gateway to new questions. In this infinitely complex universe, perhaps the greatest discovery is to realize that, no matter the size of the Russian doll we open, there will always be another, smaller or larger, to explore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generation cost: &lt;a href="https://openai.com/pricing"&gt;11469 tokens/0.06$&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-14</guid><enclosure url="https://images.theconversation.com/files/593000/original/file-20240508-19-18ljye.jpg" length="368466" type="image/jpeg"/><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Thursday, May 9th 2024</title><link>https://daylog.tcrouzet.com/2024/05/09_en/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bigthink.com/starts-with-a-bang/origin-gold/"&gt;Our best idea for the "origin of gold" doesn't add up - Big Think&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the Universe, a vast array of naturally occurring elements, from hydrogen to plutonium, exist. The origin of heavy elements like silver, iodine, tungsten, platinum, gold, mercury, and uranium has long puzzled scientists. In 2017, the detection of a neutron star-neutron star merger provided a breakthrough, revealing the creation of various heavy elements, including an astonishing amount of gold. However, recent studies suggest that neutron star mergers alone cannot explain the abundance of gold in the Universe. The periodic table elements' origins are diverse, with supernovae, merging neutron stars, and planetary nebulae playing crucial roles. When exploring the cosmos, assumptions are made based on observed data, but biases can arise from limited observations, highlighting the need for comprehensive data collection to improve our understanding of the Universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.jpost.com/science/article-800095"&gt;Scientists perform research build robots that move like animals - The Jerusalem Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robotics engineers have long tried to create robots that can match animals in running abilities. Animals excel in agility, range, and robustness, traits robots struggle to replicate. Researchers compared the performance of engineering subsystems in running robots with their biological counterparts and found that animals still outperform robots at the whole system level. Despite the rapid progress in robotics, animals have a significant advantage due to millions of years of evolution. The study aims to guide future robot technology development towards better integration and control of existing hardware for improved efficiency and agility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Analyse&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gold and robots, two human quests, one to understand the universe, the other to conquer it. As I read these articles, I ponder our obsession with unraveling the mysteries of creation and mimicking nature. The discovery that neutron star mergers alone do not account for the abundance of gold in the universe reminds me that, despite our progress, we are still far from grasping cosmic complexity. Similarly, the endeavor to create robots that move like animals underscores our desire to match, or even surpass, natural evolution. Yet, in light of my daily reflections, these two articles lead me to consider that perhaps we are searching in the wrong direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The universe, with its black holes and exoplanets, and robotics, with its attempts to mimic life, seem to me to be two sides of the same coin. On one hand, our quest for knowledge drives us to explore the far reaches of space, seeking answers about the origin of gold, a symbol of our insignificance in the face of cosmic vastness. On the other hand, our ambition to recreate life, to build robots that move with the grace of an animal, reveals our desire for mastery over the natural world. These efforts, though commendable, prompt me to question our ability to appreciate the beauty of the unknown and to accept the limits of our understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, these explorations, whether cosmic or technological, reflect back on our own nature. They unveil our unquenchable thirst for knowledge and our desire to surpass our own limits. But perhaps, as my reflections on ethics, currency, or even art suggest, the true quest should not be to conquer the universe or surpass nature, but to better comprehend our place in the cosmos. As I have often thought, what truly matters is not so much what we discover or create, but what these quests reveal about us. "We do not turn to history to escape reality, but to navigate reality."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generation cost: &lt;a href="https://openai.com/pricing"&gt;9700 tokens/0.07$&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-09</guid><enclosure url="https://bigthink.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/1280px-Artists_impression_of_strontium_emerging_from_a_neutron_star_merger-e1715117352265.jpg" length="167405" type="image/jpeg"/><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Wednesday, May 8th 2024</title><link>https://daylog.tcrouzet.com/2024/05/08_en/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/science/2024/05/07/earth-moon-impact-plate-tectonics/"&gt;Mysterious blobs inside Earth triggered plate tectonics, study suggests - The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.5 billion years ago, a Mars-sized object collided with Earth, creating the moon. Scientists suggest the impact also formed mysterious blobs in Earth's interior, possibly initiating plate tectonics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.iflscience.com/your-enemys-enemy-really-is-your-friend-according-to-physics-74080"&gt;Your Enemy's Enemy Really Is Your Friend – According To Physics! - IFLScience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans navigate complex and evolving social networks. Social balance theory, originating in the 1940s, posits that individuals strive for equilibrium in relationships. It outlines rules like "friend of a friend is a friend" and "enemy of an enemy is a friend." Recent research, aligning with this theory, reveals the importance of constraints and individual positivity levels in modeling social networks accurately. The study, in Science Advances, sheds light on the mathematical underpinnings of social dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.universetoday.com/166889/new-evidence-for-our-solar-systems-ghost-planet-nine/"&gt;New Evidence for Our Solar System's Ghost: Planet Nine - Universe Today&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers Mike Brown and Konstantin Batygin, along with Alessandro Morbidelli and David Nesvorny, present more evidence supporting the existence of Planet Nine (P9). Their paper, "Generation of Low-Inclination, Neptune-Crossing TNOs by Planet Nine," published in The Astrophysical Journal Letters, discusses the anomalous dynamical structure in the solar system's distant reaches hinting at P9's presence. The study examines Trans-Neptunian Objects (TNOs) with conventional orbits through N-body simulations, focusing on 17 well-quantified orbits from 29 objects in the Minor Planet Database. The researchers aim to use these objects as a probe for P9, conducting simulations with and without P9 in the Solar System.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Analyse&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The universe is not just stardust; it is also a vast network of relationships, a bit like on Facebook, but without the annoying game invitations. I often venture into reflections that take me far, very far, perhaps even to the collision that formed the Moon and initiated plate tectonics on Earth. This cataclysmic event, which shaped our world, reminds me that even in the most absolute chaos, there can be order, structure, a beginning. It's a bit like when I get lost in social networks, searching for a common thread, a logic in the midst of all the noise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I come across this theory of balance in social networks, which makes me think of the search for balance in our lives. We all try to navigate this labyrinth of friendships and enemies, to understand who is with us and who is against us. It's a bit like in space, where planets and celestial objects follow trajectories dictated by invisible forces. And then, I think that maybe understanding social dynamics is a bit like trying to predict the position of a phantom planet in our solar system. It's complex, it's fascinating, and it's a bit frustrating too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The supposed existence of Planet Nine, this mysterious object that would influence everything from the shadows, makes me reflect on the invisible yet profound impact that certain elements can have on our lives. It's like those mysterious blobs inside the Earth, or those lost friends we find on LinkedIn. We don't see them, but they are there, influencing our trajectory. And in the midst of all this, I remember that, despite our quest for understanding, connection, and discovery, we are all a bit like solitary explorers in the vastness of the universe, seeking our place, our orbit, our path. As Lisa Cron said, we seek to navigate reality, and sometimes, it's by gazing at the stars that we find our way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generation cost: &lt;a href="https://openai.com/pricing"&gt;9761 tokens/0.06$&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-08</guid><enclosure url="https://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php" length="12878" type="image/jpeg"/><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Monday, May 6th 2024</title><link>https://daylog.tcrouzet.com/2024/05/06_en/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/books/2024/05/05/alien-earths-science-book/"&gt;‘Alien Earths’ by Lisa Kaltenegger book review - The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the unknowns in science, particularly extraterrestrial life. Despite advances in astronomy and planetary science, the existence of alien life forms, from microbial to highly technological, remains uncertain. However, the topic is still worthy of exploration, prompting the writing of books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wionews.com/science/earths-life-saver-magnetic-field-collapsed-590mn-years-ago-for-all-good-reasons-718190"&gt;Earth's 'life-saver' magnetic field collapsed 590mn years ago, for all good reasons - WION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earth's magnetic field shields the planet from solar radiation. Research suggests it vanished 590 million years ago, coinciding with the Ediacaran period when multicellular life evolved. Scientists found the field weakened 30 times then, lasting 26 million years, correlating with a biodiversity explosion. The weakened field possibly led to higher oxygen levels, fueling life diversification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ladbible.com/news/science/scientists-discovery-bottom-red-sea-761201-20240502"&gt;Scientists made chilling discovery after finally reaching the bottom of the Red Sea - LADbible&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Red Sea, located between Africa and the Arabian Peninsula, is known for its vibrant ecosystem and as a busy shipping lane. Scientists discovered 'death pools' at its bottom, devoid of oxygen and home to extremophile microbes. These pools, untouched by usual marine life, offer insights into the origins of life on Earth and the potential for life on other planets. Researchers also use the pools to study past natural disasters like tsunamis and earthquakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Analyse&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The universe, this vast cosmic joke, mocks us, poor humans, who question everything. I have often pondered these questions. Articles on 'Alien Earths', the Earth's magnetic field, and the 'death pools' of the Red Sea only deepen my perplexity, blending science, conjecture, and a desire to know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one hand, the hunt for exoplanets and extraterrestrial life reignites my taste for the unknown, my desire to believe in the existence of other forms of life, perhaps even in a universal consciousness, as suggested by panpsychism. On the other hand, the story of Earth's magnetic field, its collapse, and its connection to the explosion of biodiversity, reminds me of life's ability to thrive, despite everything. Lastly, the discovery of 'death pools' in the Red Sea, these ecosystems where life thrives without oxygen, fascinates me and proves that life, in one form or another, is always possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These reflections, nurtured by my readings and observations, have led me to a conclusion: life, in its diversity, is a mystery that surpasses us. It reminds us of our insignificance in the universe, while inviting us to bear witness to it. Life, with its mysteries, is a reminder that the impossible does not exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generation cost: &lt;a href="https://openai.com/pricing"&gt;9790 tokens/0.06$&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-06</guid><enclosure url="https://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php" length="12878" type="image/jpeg"/><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item></channel></rss>